Guide to the Rice University KTRU Radio records, 1962-2018 UA 011
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series I: Audio recordings, 1968-2007, 59004
  - Sub-Series: 1971/1972
    - News Master 2, Summer 1971; wrc06225; 59031 (Box 1)
      Contents include: (00:01) Description of new courses; (00:27) Written evaluation of course work; (1:00) Summer construction and renovation projects Sewall Hall, Jones College, Baker College; (01:42) Seismic expert on Apollo 14; (02:45) Mickey Swift in Mecom Fountain. Speakers: Mickey Swift, Herman Beiersdorf
    - Sen. Ralph Yarborough speech, 1971-10-09; wrc07913 (Box 1)
      Contents include: Sen. Ralph Yarborough speaks at Rice about the youth vote, increasing voter turnout, his accomplishments, and proposed new legislation that he supports. We deleted extraneous audio at the end of this recording. Speakers: Ralph Yarborough
    - Sid Richardson College dedication, 1971-10-16; wrc07914 (Box 1)
      Contents include: Part of this recording was interrupted by an unrelated radio broadcast. We deleted it. (00:01) Short prayer; (02:25) Introduction; (05:53) Perry Richardson Bass speech; (11:56) Jerry Gallagher speech; (14:12) Dr. J. Venn Leeds speech; (18:18) John F. Heard speech; (19:38) Norman Hackerman speech; (21:35) Pres. Lyndon B. Johnson speech; (42:10) Carey Croneis closing remarks. Part of this recording was interrupted by an unrelated radio broadcast. We deleted it. There are also technical issues with this recording, because of its age. Speakers: Carey Croneis, Perry Richardson Bass, Jerry Gallagher, J. Venn Leeds, John F. Heard, Norman Hackerman, Lyndon B. Johnson
    - Fred Hofheinz speaking at Rice, 1971-10-25; wrc06226; 59041 (Box 1)
      Contents include: Houston Mayoral candidate Fred Hofheinz speaking at Rice on the following topics: police department, city pollution, mass transportation, sewage treatment plant, parks and recreation, firefighters, school district, racial integration, city charter amendments. This does not include a complete speech, but instead has sound clips from a press conference. Speaker: Fred Hofheinz
    - News Master and elections, 1971-11-06, 1971-12-07; wrc07321 (Box 1)
      Contents include: (00:01) Scott Hochberg speaks with Dr. Claude de Bremaecker about the Amchitka nuclear blast on 1971-11-06; (03:50) Updates on the Houston elections; (07:58) Student Association Senate meeting on the judiciary; (08:35) Jess Neely inducted in the National Football Hall of Fame; (09:11) Associated Press headlines; (09:51) Peace Fair; (10:19) Station promo; (10:51) Updates on the Houston elections, statement from Fred Hofheinz. We deleted extraneous audio between news segments. Speakers: Paul Hlavinka, Scott Hochberg, Claude de Bremaecker, Chip Landsdale, Fred Hofheinz, Kevin Mayer, Jenny Atkins, Jim Latimer, Johnnie Buzek, Fred Hofheinz
    - Houston city election runoff coverage, 1971-12-07; wrc06227; 59042 (Box 1)
      Contents include: Houston election night coverage; Reports on India and East Pakistan. Speakers: Fred Hofheinz, Kevin Mayer, Jenny Atkins, Jim Latimer
    - News Master 1a, Fall 1971; wrc06228; 59037 (Box 1)
      Contents include: (00:01) Student Association Homecoming boycott resolution; (00:18) Rice Owls football on Bruce Gad; (00:36) Campus power failure; (00:44) Pasadena school board meeting; (01:22) Co-ed colleges; (2:00) Rice Owls Football vs. Alabama preview; (03:00) Frank Vandiver announcement on Hurricane Fern; (03:19) Owl hooting; (03:54) Rice Owls Football vs. University of Southern California preview, Eddie Collins, Chris Hale; (05:15) University fund drive; (06:03) Texas legislature scandals; (06:43) Huddo trial and convictions; (08:08) Curtis Graves on Texas legislature scandals; (09:28) Rice Program Council news; (09:53) Norman Hackerman on Rice Commerce Department; (10:38) Jones College news; (11:31) Honor Council elections; (11:59) Daniel Ellsberg's Pentagon Papers; (12:41) AP college football poll; (13:18) Football unclear; (13:51) Football; (14:33) Rice Owls Football; (15:09) Religion and black people; (16:38) Football fundraising; (17:40) Off campus funds; (18:38) Norman Hackerman on tuition; (19:55) Debbie Leonard Socialist Party for mayor; (20:57) RPC The Sticks bicycle tour; (23:05) Norman Hackerman on existence; (24:10) Sticks bicycle tour; (25:53) Sewal Hall dedication; (26:23) Rice Owls Football vs. Tulane review; (27:08) Quadraphonic sound review; (28:33) Texas stock scandal; (29:29) Democratic meet; (30:26) Rice Owls Football vs. Louisiana State University preview, athletic awards, freshman football; (32:50) Bills on Health Services and India Student Association; (32:44) Resolutions by senate; (34:05) Student Association; (34:23) Rice Owls Football vs. Louisiana State University; (35:41) Rice Owls Football vs. LSU review; (36:28) HISD Citizenship Committee, school board elections. Speakers: Bill Peterson, Norman Hackerman, Jeff Landsdale, John Doerr
    - News Master 1b, Fall 1971; wrc06229; 59040 (Box 1)
      Contents include: (00:01) Dr. Edward Norbeck on play; (00:49) Student Association elections in the colleges; (01:51) Greater Houston Convention and Visitors Council on Super Bowl invitation; (02:46) Rice TexPIRG elections; (03:45) Rice Owls baseball vs. Southern Methodist University review; (04:43) Rice Owls track and field meet preview; (06:25) SA election invalid; (07:25) Rice Owls baseball vs. Southern Methodist University review; (08:15) Rice Owls track and field meet review; (09:35) TexPIRG local board elections; (10:26) EPA lawsuit against Cedar Bayou Plant; (11:21) SA elections; (13:31) Super Bowl in Rice Stadium; (14:34) Texas delegates in Democratic Party Convention, rule changes; (15:36) Robert Pierpoint on his visit to China with Pres. Richard Nixon; (16:20) SA elections; (17:05) Bussing issue, racism; (17:41) SA elections; (18:29) Co-ed colleges; (19:29) Norman Hackerman on co-ed colleges; (22:10) Rice Owls track and field meet review and preview; (23:30) SA elections; (27:09) Financial aid; (27:56) State and federal board of educations against Harris County board for redistricting; (28:36) Counterfeit food stamp cards; (29:24) Bachelor of Fine Arts; (29:47) New Director of County Health Department; (30:59) Federal court restraining order, vice squad on lewd dancing; (32:17) SA elections; (33:29) Astrodome event; (33:58) Director of County Health Department; (34:29) University of Houston alcohol on campus; (35:01) Energy consumption; (35:37) Trans-Alaska oil pipeline; (36:48) Meat import quotas; (37:44) Padre Island rock concert; (38:33) School of Architecture Dean David A. Crane hired; (39:01) Rice Owls baseball vs. Trinity University preview; (39:31) Drug treatment centers. Speakers: Larry Le May, Robert Pierpoint, Norman Hackerman, Jim Ray, John Doerr, Mike Ross
    - News Master 2, Fall 1971; wrc06230; 59038 (Box 2)
      Contents include: (00:01) Rice Owls sports review; (00:44) Presidential and other election results; (01:27) Off-campus; (02:06) Citizens for Good Schools election endorsement; (02:52) Lt. Governor Ben Barnes speaking at Rice; (03:35) Debbie Leonard, Fred Hofhienz, and Louie Welch speaking at Rice; (04:37) "Rice and City of Houston in the 70s" seminars; (05:42) Apollo 14 water on the moon; (06:53) Overview of Debbie Leonard's speech; (07:37) Apollo 14 moon findings; (08:17)Rice Owls Football on team; (09:00) Pres. Lyndon Johnson's Sid Richardson College dedication speech; (16:01) Issues at KPFT Pacifica radio station; (20:36) Co-ed college proposal; (22:36) KPFT Pacifica strike; (22:38) Financial Aid Office organization; (23:30) Rice Owls Football; (23:56) KPFT Pacifica strike; (29:06) Rice Owls Football vs. Texas review; (31:02) KPFT Pacifica strike; (31:58) Fred Hofheinz campaign speech on law enforcement and water pollution in Houston; (34:40) Student Association recommendations to commencement exercises; (35:34) Rice Owls Football vs. Tech preview, player motivation; (36:47) Student proposal; (37:11) KPFT Pacifica update; (39:05) Spring registration; (39:44) KPFT Pacifica strike; (40:36) Rice soccer team vs. St. Thomas University; (41:07) Louie Welch supports Herman Short; (41:55) Thomas Moore manuscripts found by Wilfred S. Dowden; (43:10) Rice Owls football vs. Tech review; (46:14) Drug symposium; (47:38) Telefund training. Speakers: Fred Hofheinz, Bill Peterson, Scott Hochberg
    - News Master 3, Fall 1971; wrc06231; 59039 (Box 2)
      Contents include: (00:01) Nuclear Fusion with plasma; (01:12) Student interest in university finances; (02:36) New pledges from fund drive; (02:59) Students and Development Office; (03:22) AP Player of the Week Rodrigo Barnes; (04:13) 2001 view of the future speech; (04:53) Student on Rice University Fund Council; (05:35) Annual fund drive; (06:16) Rice Owls football offense; (07:06) Carl Smith proposed 40th precinct redrawn; (07:49) Rice Owls football; (08:45) Norman Hackerman at Hanszen College, alumni funds; (09:30) Editorial on students and the fund drive; (10:14) Louie Welch at Hanszen College; (10:34) No compromise; (10:47) Vietnam War and Pres. Richard Nixon; (12:00) Jones College completions; (12:29) Rice Owls basketball offense; (13:10) Student Association on discrimination; (13:41) School board candidates at Hanszen College; (14:10) KPFT Pacifica fundraising; (14:39) Golden age of epigenetic development; (15:22) Rice Owls football vs. Texas A and M; (16:03) Louie Welch on Herman Short; (16:25) Rice Owls football passing; (17:04) SWC conference standings; (17:58) Rice Owls football recruiting; (19:04) Changes to voting precinct lines; (19:48) Telefund update; (21:48) Frank E. Vandiver and Allan Nevins publication of "The Papers of Jefferson Davis, Vol. I, 1808-1840"; (21:47) Telefund update; (24:23) Offensive Player of the Week, Bruce Gadd; (25:03) Rice Owls football vs. Texas A and M preview; (25:55) Student Financial Aid Committee on Telefund; (27:29) Rice Owls football vs. Texas A and M preview; (27:55) SWC football weekend; (29:20) Population growth and regulation; (30:51) Financial aid news; (32:14) Bill Peterson on using Rice Co-eds for recruitment; (33:07) Will Rice Diet on minority admissions; (33:32) Rice Owls football vs. Texas Christian University; (34:51) Voter busing; (35:31) KPFT Pacifica marathon; (36:56) Voting in precinct 40; (37:31:) Clark Read on falling strings; (38:08) School board elections; (38:39) Blanket tax increase for subscription series; (39:49) Clark Read on falling strings; (40:04) Bella Abzug at Sheraton Lincoln; (41:24) Judson W. Robinson, Jr. thanks Jones College; (42:07) Clark Reed on falling strings; (42:34) Fundraising in Dallas and Fort Worth; (43:26) Student vote and election; (44:27) Harris County Clerk fired; (45:10) Warren Scarren and Preston Smith on film in Texas; (46:04) Children of God colonies; (46:45) United Press International announces All SWC team. Speakers: Bill Peterson, Norman Hackerman, Louie Welch, Jim Latimer, Clark Read, Judson W. Robinson, Jr.
    - News Master 4, Fall 1971; wrc06232; 59032 (Box 2)
      Contents include: (00:01) Invitation to Wordsworthless Society Meeting; (00:50) Arthur W. Bush regional administrator of EPA; (01:31) Football recruiting; (02:00) Football player interview; (02:24) Interview about East Pakistan; (03:21) Regional EPA administration roles and power; (04:14) Student Association meeting on student judicial issues; (05:13) Rice Program Council on Blanket Tax increase; (06:12) Blood donations; (06:23) Rice University Court women and minority representatives; (07:02) Leslie and Larry Owens Memorial Service; (07:16) Telefund contributions; (07:59) SA referendum on minority admission fails; (08:21) Unapproved care packages; (09:10) Senator's report on students on University Court; (10:51) Election shuttle; (11:40) Basketball Coach Don Knodel on student support of basketball; (12:14) Basketball Coach Don Knodel on young basketball team; (13:44) Basketball Coach Don Knodel on Rice Owls vs. Citadel; (14:26) Basketball Coach Don Knodel on starting line up; (15:18) Rice Owls Basketball vs. Wake Forest Demon Deacons and sports; (16:35) Mayor Louie Welch assessment; (17:01) Fred Hofheinz mayoral election prediction; (17:55) Mayoral election prediction; (18:56) Electioneering by precinct judge; (19:20) Unknown woman on working in schools; (19:40) Fred Hofheinz - fresh look at city hall (20:13) Position 7 election; (20:29) Local politician on his election race; (20:52) Local politician on student voting; (21:03) Election shuttle; (21:51) Students primarily not radicals; (22:28) Conservative voting turnout; (22:51) Complacency reducing voter turnout; (23:12) Mayor Louie Welch angers black community; (21:42) Fred Hofheinz on Mayor Louie Welch's treatment of black neighborhoods; (24:24) Local politician on his election race; (24:57) Fred Hofheinz vote for change; (25:32) Problems of younger people voting at precincts; (26:30) RPC blanket tax referendum; (27:30) ACLU contacts for voter assistance; (28:03) Rice Owls basketball vs San Jacinto Ravens; (28:52) Santa ad for RPC Christmas party; (29:26) Local politician on education; (30:12) University Court; (30:56) Supreme Court and William Rehnquist; (31:32) Politician calling for end of involvement in Southeast Asia; (32:10) Young coaching staff; (32:28) Registrar's Office on schedules; (33:10) Marine Science research; (34:09) Geological evolution about an unknown planet; (34:57) Basketball Coach Don Knodel talking about a game; (35:43) Basketball Coach Don Knodel getting rid of freshman team; (36:45) Basketball Coach Don Knodel on Georgia Tech; (37:37) Possible recruitment of Joe Washington for football staff; (38:45) Coach view on athlete's student life; (40:05) Friction between students and athletic department; (41:20) Marine research bioerosion; (42:37) Rice Owls Basketball vs. Hawaii Rainbow Warriors, Coach Bill Peterson going to Houston Oilers, appointed Athletic Director Red Bale and Football Coach Al Conover; (44:18) Texas Public Interest Research Group on ethics, pollution, racial issues; (45:30) Unknown person talking about recent appointment; (46:04) The Owl Club construction; (47:00) Changes in policies at HISD; (47:38) Pete McCloskey running against President Nixon. Speakers: Don Knodel, Mike Ross, Louie Welch, Fred Hofheinz
    - FM 91.7 Pacifica strike interview, 1972-01-06; wrc06233; 59050 (Box 2)
      Contents include: Former DJ of Pacifica Radio Station 91.7 FM covering the Pacifica worker's strike, subscribers' meetings, and issues with the Pacifica board. Speaker: Walt Silvus
    - So Now You Can Vote, 1972-02-29, 1972-03-21; wrc06235; 59051 (Box 2)
      Contents include: Episode 1972-02-29: Interview with Frances Farenthold running for Governor of Texas. She discusses the other candidates, corruption, and pollution; Coverage of the upcoming New Hampshire primary; Episode 1972-03-21: Florida primary results; Interview with Counting Chairman of Harris County Mr. Bouley for George Wallace. He discusses bussing, budget deficit, and youth vote. This audio has been altered to fix technical difficulties. Speakers: Scott Hockberg, Hubert Humphrey, George McGovern
    - News Master 5, Spring 1972; wrc06234; 59047 (Box 2)
      Contents include: (00:01) HISD retirement policy; (00:48) Used book fair; (01:23) Edward Muskie campaign; (01:49) New screening for cervical and lung cancer; (02:50) Pres. Norman Hackerman on co-owners of Rice Stadium; (03:21) Rice Owls basketball vs. University of Texas review; (04:41) Unclear; (05:17) SWC Sportsmanship Committee and award, financial aid for athletes; (06:58) Al Conover on Limiting athletic scholarships and based on need, football awards; (09:35) Larger stadium in Houston; (10:03) Football awards banquet; (11:04) NFL recruitment of Bill Peterson; (12:41) TexPIRG on campus; (13:26) Co-ed college not expanding because of donor issues; (14:25) Two new co-ed colleges; (15:36) Co-ed colleges and student housing; (17:08) Rice Program Council subscription series; (18:14) Astroworld demonstration; (19:00) Graduate students poverty volunteering; (19:44) TexPIRG on campus; (22:00) Rice Owls basketball vs. Texas Tech preview; (22:32) Rice Program Council subscription series; (24:00) Professor's credentials; (24:29) Carey Croneis memorial; (24:50) Rice Owls basketball preview; (25:50) Influenza in Houston; (26:16) Speaker from Carey Croneis memorial; (27:30) Pres. Richard Nixon on Vietnam War de-escalation plans; (29:01) Moon eclipse; (29:40) Co-ed college committee report; (30:28) Rice Owls basketball review; (31:57) Freshman to play on varsity squads rule change; (32:47) Narcotics officer resigned, Dennis Daniels; (33:25:) SWC basketball review; (34:17) Death of Fred Wolcott; (35:00) University Council committee elections; (35:10) Improved health services survey; (35:45) Special city election; (36:50) Voter registration rules; (37:23) Phone survey about odor; (38:27) Hanszen College opposes building of R club room; (39:36) Rules for dogs on campus; (40:28) Opposing building of R club room; (42:25) Rice Owls swimming meet review; (43:24) Accepted athletic job at Rice; (44:02) American Basketball Association drafting college players; (46:30) Rice Owls basketball vs. Texas A and M preview, rebounding. Speakers: Scott Hochberg, Mike Ross, Al Conover, Jim Latimer, Doug Welty, Don Knodel
    - News Master 6, Spring 1972; wrc06236; 59049 (Box 2)
      Contents include: (00:01) Investigating organized crime; (1:00) Open meeting on voting precints; (01:56) Kim ruled ineligible; (03:42) Conference rules and NCAA rules; (04:15) Will Rice College elections; (04:54) Lovett College elections; (05:14) Rice Owlettes vs. University of Southwestern Louisiana preview; (05:43) Santiago Genoves speaking at Rice; (06:20) Vietnam War draft number request call-in; (07:10) Student body demonstration [?]; (07:48) Earliest evidence of sex among organisms; (08:29) NFL draft, Stahle Vincent, Bob Brown, Mike Tyler; (08:57) Hexachlorophene not used to bathe babies; (09:42) Speaker talking about TexPIRG; (10:10) Election names; (10:21) Sidney Burrus taking over for another professor; (10:36) Rice Owls basketball vs. University of Arkansas review; (11:19) Student government at Rice; (12:11) Polling places; (12:30) University Council at Large Kathleen Ford; (12:48) Russia and the U.S. space exploration; (13:44) Chaplain services at local jails; (15:13) Joe Highland meeting on TexPIRG petition; (16:44) Appeal of legal decision; (17:10) Teacher education program; (18:09) Water quality board; (19:13) Texas Governor's race; (20:28) Clockwork Orange film review; (21:21) Will Rice College elections; (21:37) TexPIRG speaker; (22:29) Economic growth. Speakers: Mike Benning, Mike Ross, Larry Le May, Wayne Baisley
    - News Master 7, Spring 1972; wrc06237; 59048 (Box 2)
      Contents include: (00:01) Economic growth; (01:15) Al Conover on Rice Owls football signings; (02:37) Champion Papers on water quality; (03:18) HISD change of retirement policy, union; (04:00) Trial; (04:20) Water quality rules; (05:59) Ralph Nader in Texas, TexPIRG; (06:57) Democrat Convention delegates, Anderson Rules; (08:30) Hanszen College election results; (09:26) Rice Chorale program; (10:28) Anti-Nixon activist at Sewall Hall; (10:48) Robert R. Herring and William H. Lane elected to Board of Trustees; (11:32) Architectural students take trip; (12:19) Valentine's Sweetheart Carolyn Rindosh; (12:51) Pres. Richard Nixon's trip to China; (14:22) Father Meyendorff speaking at Rice; (15:11) Houston consumer affairs; (15:44) Bird problem at Fondren Library and at local business; (16:27) University of Houston financial aid; (17:17) end of season SWC basketball review; (18:17) Robert Pierpoint to speak at Rice on Pres. Richard Nixon's China trip; (18:34) Drug abuse stabilized at Rice University; (19:26) Brown College elections; (19:53) Washington, DC Environmental Organization ecotage contest; (21:11) HISD school board; (22:07) Rice Owls tennis review and preview; (23:37) Terry Sanford presidential campaign review; (24:49) New York State University, Stoneybrook dog problem; (25:23) Rice Owls tennis review; (26:18) Rice Owls swimming review; (28:18) Dr. Virgil W. Topazio given endowed chair; (29:20) Pioneer 10 mission, Viking program; (32:00) Rice Owls basketball vs. TCU preview; (32:46) Harold Solomon not going pro; (33:34) Abortion laws; (34:16) Police and African American community relations in Houston; (35:05) Rice Owls basketball vs. TCU review; (37:22) Model Neighborhood Residents Commission. Speakers: Al Conover, Larry Le May, Sandy Moss, Bill Lee
    - News Master 10, Spring 1972; wrc06238; 59043 (Box 2)
      Contents include: (00:01) Drug addiction treatment; (00:58) Anthropology collection for researchers; (01:30) Report of marijuana use; (03:12) Rice Owls baseball vs. Trinity University review; (03:38) Voter registration; (04:20) George McGovern campaign in Texas; (05:01) Lovett College opinion poll secession from Student Association Senate; (05:52) Terry Sanford presidential campaign; (06:26) Ombudsmen for Youth Affairs in Texas; (07:28) Rice Owls baseball vs. University of Texas review; (08:38) Black issues panel, concert, dance, and art exhibit; (10:14) Oxford philosophy professor on campus; (11:45) Political corruption because of low pay; (12:45) Harold Urey on creation of solar system; (13:13) Williams, golf team dispute; (13:52) Frederick T. Wall joins Chemistry Department; (14:32) Showcase of the arts at Rice; (15:18) Rice Owls baseball vs. University of Houston review; (15:59) Electrical outage at Rice; (16:40) Apollo 16 launch; (17:48) TexPIRG election; (17:55) Apollo 16 launch; (18:37) Federal laws on marijuana; (19:21) Reform of drug laws; (19:58) Student elections and registration; (20:33) Fire damage to Baker College room; (22:25) Rice Owls baseball vs. Lamar University review; (23:36) IM baseball review; (24:21) Trial lawyer on judges; (27:23) Rice student misdemeanor, felony charges for anti-war demonstration; (28:07) Blue gray game; (28:42) All-American Intercollegiate Invitational Tournament golf review; (29:36) Strike at unknown university; (30:21) Gov. Preston Smith on economy, social issues; (32:27) Student Association election ballot controversy; (33:23) Student consultants on university committees given more standing; (34:01) Reduction of degree requirements; (34:37) Student Association polling places; (35:22) Artificial heart valves; (36:00) Pres. Richard Nixon on Vietnam negotiations; (36:53) Faculty reducing degree requirements. Because of the tape's condition, the audio is damaged. Speakers: Sandy Moss, Jenny Atkins, Rick Cordray, Bill Lee, David Real, Richard Nixon, Preston Smith
    - Rice Summer School promos, 1972-00-00; wrc07912 (Box 2)
      Contents include: Promos for the Rice University summer school program for high school students from the Education Department. Speakers: Scott Hochberg
  - Sub-Series: 1972/1973, 59052
    - Democratic Convention wrap-up, Summer 1972; wrc06239; 59008 (Box 2)
      Contents include: The radio show "So Now You Can Vote" reviews the 1972 Democratic Convention and how George McGovern received the nomination. Speakers: Mike Ross, Scott Hochberg, Shirley Chisholm, George McGovern, Valerie Kushner
    - Sissy Speaks Out, 1972-10-30; wrc06240; 59007 (Box 2)
      Contents include: Interview with Frances Tarlton "Sissy" Farenthold about presidential candidate George McGovern, the Vietnam War, Pres. Richard Nixon, move to Houston, and the Democratic Convention. Speaker: Sissy Farenthold
    - George McGovern speeches in Houston, 1972-10; wrc06241; 59009 (Box 2)